the-gadgeteer.com 2018-12-26

# Privacy and Cookie Policy – The Gadgeteer

_**Last updated May 01, 2018**_

The Gadgeteer (“we” or “us” or “our”) respects the privacy of our users (“user” or “you”). This Privacy Policy  
explains how we collect, use, disclose, and safeguard your information when you visit our website [https://thegadgeteer.](https://thegadgeteer.com/)  
com including any other media form, media channel, mobile website, or mobile application related or  
connected thereto (collectively, the “Site”). Please read this Privacy Policy carefully. **IF YOU DO NOT AGREE**  
**WITH THE TERMS OF THIS PRIVACY POLICY, PLEASE DO NOT ACCESS THE SITE**.

We reserve the right to make changes to this Privacy Policy at any time and for any reason. We will alert you  
about any changes by updating the “Revised” date of this Privacy Policy. Any changes or modifications will be  
effective immediately upon posting the updated Privacy Policy on the Site, and you waive the right to receive  
specific notice of each such change or modification. You are encouraged to periodically review this Privacy Policy  
to stay informed of updates. You will be deemed to have been made aware of, will be subject to, and will be  
deemed to have accepted the changes in any revised Privacy Policy by your continued use of the Site after the  
date such revised Privacy Policy is posted.

**COLLECTION OF YOUR INFORMATION**

We may collect information about you in a variety of ways. The information we may collect on the Site includes:

**Personal Data**

Personally identifiable information, such as your name, shipping address, email address, and telephone number,  
and demographic information, such as your age, gender, hometown, and interests, that you voluntarily give to us  
when you choose to participate in various activities related to the Site, such as online chat and message boards.  
You are under no obligation to provide us with personal information of any kind, however your refusal to do so  
may prevent you from using certain features of the Site.

**Derivative Data**

Information our servers automatically collect when you access the Site, such as your IP address, your browser  
type, your operating system, your access times, and the pages you have viewed directly before and after  
accessing the Site.

**Data From Social Networks**

User information from social networking sites, such as Facebook, Twitter, Google+, AIM, Yahoo IM,  
Jabble/Google Talk, including your name, your social network username, location, gender, birth date, email  
address, profile picture, and public data for contacts, if you connect your account to such social networks.

**Data From Contests, Giveaways, and Surveys**

Personal and other information you may provide when entering contests or giveaways and/or responding to  
surveys.

**USE OF YOUR INFORMATION**

Having accurate information about you permits us to provide you with a smooth, efficient, and customized  
experience. Specifically, we may use information collected about you via the Site to:

● Administer sweepstakes, promotions, and contests.  
● Compile anonymous statistical data and analysis for use internally or with third parties.  
● Monitor and analyze usage and trends to improve your experience with the Site.  
● Notify you of updates to the Site.  
● Perform other business activities as needed.  
● Request feedback and contact you about your use of the Site.  
● Send you a newsletter.  
● Create and manage your account.  
● Email you regarding your account or order.  
● Deliver targeted advertising, coupons, newsletters, and promotions, and other information regarding our  
website and mobile application to you.  
● Solicit support for the Site.

**DISCLOSURE OF YOUR INFORMATION**

We may share information we have collected about you in certain situations. Your information may be disclosed  
as follows:

**By Law or to Protect Rights**

If we believe the release of information about you is necessary to respond to legal process, to investigate or  
remedy potential violations of our policies, or to protect the rights, property, and safety of others, we may share  
your information as permitted or required by any applicable law, rule, or regulation. This includes exchanging  
information with other entities for fraud protection and credit risk reduction.

Interactions with Other UsersIf you interact with other users of the Site, those users may see your name, profile photo, and descriptions of your activity, including sending invitations to other users, chatting with other users, liking posts, following blogs.

**Online Postings**

When you post comments, contributions or other content to the Site, your posts may be viewed by all users and  
may be publicly distributed outside the Site in perpetuity.

**Third-Party Advertisers**

We may use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit the Site. These companies may use  
information about your visits to the Site and other websites that are contained in web cookies in order to provide  
advertisements about goods and services of interest to you.

**Social Media Contacts**

If you connect to the Site through a social network, your contacts on the social network will see your name, profile  
photo, and descriptions of your activity.

**Other Third Parties**

We may share your information with advertisers and investors for the purpose of conducting general business  
analysis. We may also share your information with such third parties for marketing purposes, as permitted by law.

**Sale or Bankruptcy**

If we reorganize or sell all or a portion of our assets, undergo a merger, or are acquired by another entity, we may  
transfer your information to the successor entity. If we go out of business or enter bankruptcy, your information  
would be an asset transferred or acquired by a third party. You acknowledge that such transfers may occur and  
that the transferee may decline honor commitments we made in this Privacy Policy.  
We are not responsible for the actions of third parties with whom you share personal or sensitive data, and we  
have no authority to manage or control third-party solicitations. If you no longer wish to receive correspondence,  
emails or other communications from third parties, you are responsible for contacting the third party directly.

**TRACKING TECHNOLOGIES**

**Cookies and Web Beacons**

We may use cookies, web beacons, tracking pixels, and other tracking technologies on the Site to help customize  
the Site and improve your experience. For more information on how we use cookies, please refer to our Cookie  
Policy posted on the Site, which is incorporated into this Privacy Policy. By using the Site, you agree to be bound  
by our Cookie Policy.

**Internet-Based Advertising**

Additionally, we may use third-party software to serve ads on the Site, implement email marketing campaigns,  
and manage other interactive marketing initiatives. This third-party software may use cookies or similar tracking  
technology to help manage and optimize your online experience with us. For more information about opting-out of  
interest-based ads, visit the Network Advertising Initiative Opt-Out Tool or [Digital Advertising Alliance Opt-Out](http://optout.aboutads.info/)  
Tool.

**Website Analytics**

We may also partner with selected third-party vendors, such as Google Analytics, Crazy Egg, to allow tracking  
technologies and remarketing services on the Site through the use of first party cookies and third-party cookies,  
to, among other things, analyze and track users’ use of the Site, determine the popularity of certain content and  
better understand online activity. By accessing the Site, you consent to the collection and use of your information  
by these third-party vendors. You are encouraged to review their privacy policy and contact them directly for  
responses to your questions. We do not transfer personal information to these third-party vendors. However, If  
you do not want any information to be collected and used by tracking technologies, you can visit the third-party  
vendor or Network Advertising Initiative Opt-Out Tool or Digital Advertising Alliance Opt-Out Tool.  
You should be aware that getting a new computer, installing a new browser, upgrading an existing browser, or  
erasing or otherwise altering your browser’s cookies files may also clear certain opt-out cookies, plug-ins, or  
settings.

**THIRD-PARTY WEBSITES**

The Site may contain links to third-party websites and applications of interest, including advertisements and  
external services, that are not affiliated with us. Once you have used these links to leave the Site, any information  
you provide to these third parties is not covered by this Privacy Policy, and we cannot guarantee the safety and  
privacy of your information. Before visiting and providing any information to any third-party websites, you should  
inform yourself of the privacy policies and practices (if any) of the third party responsible for that website, and  
should take those steps necessary to, in your discretion, protect the privacy of your information. We are not  
responsible for the content or privacy and security practices and policies of any third parties, including other sites,  
services or applications that may be linked to or from the Site.

**SECURITY OF YOUR INFORMATION**

We use administrative, technical, and physical security measures to help protect your personal information. While  
we have taken reasonable steps to secure the personal information you provide to us, please be aware that  
despite our efforts, no security measures are perfect or impenetrable, and no method of data transmission can be  
guaranteed against any interception or other type of misuse. Any information disclosed online is vulnerable to  
interception and misuse by unauthorized parties. Therefore, we cannot guarantee complete security if you  
provide personal information.

**POLICY FOR CHILDREN**

We do not knowingly solicit information from or market to children under the age of 13. If you become aware of  
any data we have collected from children under age 13, please contact us using the contact information provided  
below.

**CONTROLS FOR DO-NOT-TRACK FEATURES**

Most web browsers and some mobile operating systems include a Do-Not-Track (“DNT”) feature or setting you  
can activate to signal your privacy preference not to have data about your online browsing activities monitored  
and collected. No uniform technology standard for recognizing and implementing DNT signals has been finalized.  
As such, we do not currently respond to DNT browser signals or any other mechanism that automatically  
communicates your choice not to be tracked online. If a standard for online tracking is adopted that we must  
follow in the future, we will inform you about that practice in a revised version of this Privacy Policy.

**CALIFORNIA PRIVACY RIGHTS**

California Civil Code Section 1798.83, also known as the “Shine The Light” law, permits our users who are  
California residents to request and obtain from us, once a year and free of charge, information about categories  
of personal information (if any) we disclosed to third parties for direct marketing purposes and the names and  
addresses of all third parties with which we shared personal information in the immediately preceding calendar  
year. If you are a California resident and would like to make such a request, please submit your request in writing  
to us using the contact information provided below.  
If you are under 18 years of age, reside in California, and have a registered account with the Site, you have the  
right to request removal of unwanted data that you publicly post on the Site. To request removal of such data,  
please contact us using the contact information provided below, and include the email address associated with  
your account and a statement that you reside in California. We will make sure the data is not publicly displayed  
on the Site, but please be aware that the data may not be completely or comprehensively removed from our  
systems.

**CONTACT US**  
If you have questions or comments about this Privacy Policy, please contact us at:

The Gadgeteer  
Columbus, IN 47201  
United States  
Phone: (812) 408 – 9613  
info@the-gadgeteer.com
